ptcl.com.pk 2019-05-28

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy for PTCL Website ([www.ptcl.com.pk](http://www.ptcl.com.pk/)) is to be read and used in connection with the Terms & Conditions which are also published on this website.

This privacy policy has been formulated to assist Customers /Website Users to understand how their personal information will be treated by PTCL when they visit the website, as PTCL’s objective is to make available a good experience and quality service to all Customers and /or Users.

Please note that PTCL may amend this policy from time to time without prior notice. Users/ Customers are advised to check this Policy on regular basis.

**1\. Introduction**

This statement outlines customers’ rights to their personal information, and contains general principles that apply to the handling of customers’ personal information while using any of PTCL’s products or services, websites, applications and any product or service that we offer in conjunction with our partners. Depending on the product or service, customers may also receive service- specific and/or region-specific terms. Customers will be legally bound by both this statement and the service/region specific term to the extent that the customers have accepted them when signing up to service or product; therefore, customers are required to read these terms carefully.

**2\. Type of Information collected**

**a. Non Personal Information:**

PTCL may collect certain non-personal information such as customers Internet Protocol ("IP") address, operating system, browser type, and Internet service provider. This type of information does not identify the customer personally. When the customer register with the Website or Application, or respond to advertisements or posts on the Website or Application, or post content on the Website without registering, we may also collect personal information that customers provide such as their name, mailing address, email address, phone/mobile number, home country, and zip code ("Registration Information"). Customers have the option and may also provide us with their fax numbers, gender, age, and/or company name if and when they choose to register.

**b. Personal Information:**

Further, in the event customers have provided their phone numbers and posted an advertisement using their account, they impliedly agree to receive communication on the provided phone number from our side which may include but not be limited to automated calls or text messages. The communication may require customers to confirm and verify that their account has been used to post the relevant advertisement on the Website or used to provide services of the Application. We may also collect additional information that our users provide.

**c. Correspondence:**

We may also send you any legally required notifications including but not limited to, service related notices or notices regarding a change to any of our policies. For example, we may send you a notice regarding server problems or scheduled maintenance to the Website. We will not change your preferences without your consent. You cannot opt out of receiving transactional communications from PTCL related to your account.

**d. Third Party entities**

We use a third-party credit card processing company for purchases, and other third party companies to monitor site traffic, which may, in some instances, store customers information. By using this Website or the Application Service, customers consent to collection, storage, and use of the personal information for any of the services that we offer, and their consent to our collection of any changes or updates that they may provide that is collected by PTCL.

**e. Cookies**

We may use cookies to manage our users’ sessions and to store preferences, tracking information, and language selection. Cookies may be used whether customers register with us or not. "Cookies" are small text files transferred by a web server to users’ hard drive and thereafter stored on their computer. The types of information a cookie collects include the date and time users visited, their browsing history, preferences, and username. In some instances, our third-party service providers may use cookies on the Website or Application. We cannot control or access cookies used by third- party service providers. This Privacy Policy covers only Cookies used by us, and not any cookies used by third parties. Customers may have the ability to either accept or decline the use of cookies on your computer, whether registered with us or not.  Typically, you can configure your browser to not accept cookies. However, declining the use of cookies may limit your access to certain features of the Website.

**3\. Customers Rights**

Please find below a non-exclusive list of privacy rights that customers could exercise whilst entrusting us with their information:

a. Right to withdraw consent: Where customer has consented for us to use, process, or share their personal information, customers can withdraw that consent any time, unless the information is required for us to perform our services.

b. Right to access customer’s information: Customer can access and request a copy of the personal information that we hold about them at any time by contacting us, or access the information directly through their online account.

c. Right to erasure: Customers may request that we erase some of the personal information we hold about them, provided that certain circumstances apply, such as:

I. The information is no longer needed by us and there is no legal requirement on us to retain the information.

II. Customer object to our profiling of their information, also in instances where the profiling is conducted for direct marketing purposes.

III. Other legal grounds which permit customers to do so.

**4\. PTCL’s undertaking**

a. We will process our customers or users personal information in accordance with this privacy statement and all applicable laws.

b. We will do our best to remain transparent on how we handle our customer’s personal information.

c. We will only process their personal information for legitimate purposes, and only for as long as it is necessary to achieve those purposes. We will dispose of customer’s personal information safely and securely once it is no longer required.

d. We will enable customers to exercise choice and control over our processing of their personal information, not only when we are required to do so by the applicable law, but also in other circumstances where we think it is the right thing to do.

e. We will inform customers about their privacy rights, respect them and help them to exercise those rights.

f. We will make sure that our customers’ personal information is safe through appropriate security measures.

g. We will take steps to ensure that our customers’ personal information is adequately protected.

h. We build privacy and data protection into our products and services by design and by default. This means that we prioritize the privacy of our customers’ data, and we will endeavor to build privacy safeguards in everything we develop.

i. We will only process our customers’ personal information for legitimate purposes, and only for as long as it is necessary to achieve those purposes. We will dispose of their personal information safely and securely once it is no longer required subject to applicable laws for retention of data.

**5\. Notification of Changes**

We reserve the right to change these Terms from time to time, and at our sole discretion. We may send customers a notice regarding material changes to these Terms, including the Privacy Policy or the Website.

**6\. Disputes**

Any disputes regarding customers privacy are subject to the Terms, including but not limited to any provisions related to indemnification, limitations on damages, and choice of law and forum.

**7\. Disclosures**

On rare occasions, we may be required to disclose customers’ personal information due to legal or regulatory requirements. In such instances, we reserve the right to disclose users or customers’ personal information as required by law, in order to comply with our legal obligations, including but not limited to complying with court orders, warrants, subpoenas, service of process requirements, or discovery requests. We may also disclose information about our users and/or customers to law enforcement officers or others, in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce these Terms and/or Privacy Policy; respond to claims that any Content violates the rights of third-parties; or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of PTCL, our users or the general public. Customers agree and acknowledge that we may not inform them prior to or after disclosures made according to this section. If substantially all of our assets are sold or merged into another company, the acquiring company shall be given access to customers’ personal information without their consent. If we sell only a part of our business, the acquiring entity shall have access to customers’ personal information without their consent and we may send a notice regarding this sale.

**8\. INDEMNITY**

Customers agree to defend, indemnify and hold harmless PTCL, its officers, subsidiaries, affiliates, successors, assigns, directors, officers, agents, service providers, suppliers and employees, from and against any and all claims, damages, obligations, losses, liabilities, costs or debt, and expenses (including but not limited to attorneys' fees) arising from: (i) users/customers use of and access to the Website and/or the Application Service; (ii) users/customers violation of any term of these Terms; (iii) users/customers violation of any third party right, including without limitation any copyright, trademark, trade secret or other property, or privacy right; or (iv) any claim that users/customers Content caused damage to a third party. This defense and indemnification obligation will survive termination, modification or expiration of these Terms and your use of the Application Service and the Website.

**Permissions in app:**

Access permission for:

**Device & App history**

Allows the App to view one or more of: information about activity on the device which Apps are running, browsing history and bookmarks

**Device ID & call information**

Allows the App to determine the phone number, network information and device IDs, whether a call is active and the remote number connected by a call.

**Contacts**

Uses contact information

**SMS**

Uses one or more of: SMS, MMS. To read or send either. Charges may apply

**Phone**

Uses one or more of: phone, call log. Charges may apply

**Location**

Uses the device’s location

**Wi-Fi connection information**

Allows the App to view information about Wi-Fi networking, such as whether Wi-Fi is enabled and names of connected Wi-Fi devices

**Photos/ Media/ Files**

Uses one or more of: files on the device such as images, videos or audio; the device’s external storage
